theperfectpalette.com 2019-06-12

# POLICIES | The Perfect Palette

**Privacy and Data Policy**

Revised and posted as of May 18, 2018

The Perfect Palette LLC has always prioritized the privacy of our community and has integrated this into how we conduct our business and the site that we built.

The Perfect Palette LLC., (“The Perfect Palette”) owns and operates this website (the “Site”) and other pages and mobile applications (collectively the “The Perfect Palette Sites”). The Perfect Palette LLC also operates a vendor guide, known as The Perfect Palette Vendor Guide, which is comprised of businesses to which we provide online advertising services.

The Perfect Palette Network consists of the The Perfect Palette LLC Sites, and websites owned by third-party publishers displaying The Perfect Palette LLC branding and/or The Perfect Palette LLC's logos (“Affiliated Sites”; together with the The Perfect Palette Sites, the “The Perfect Palette LLC Network”).

This Privacy and Security Policy applies to (i) the collection of information on the The Perfect Palette LLC Sites that link to or display this Privacy and Security Policy and the use of that information, (ii) the collection of information on the Affiliated Sites and the use of that information when you view ads from our advertisers, and (iii) the collection of information on the Non-Affiliated Sites and the use of that information when you view ads from our advertisers.

**1\. Information We Collect:** When you visit The Perfect Palette LLC or a Non-Affiliated Site and view ads from The Perfect Palette LLC's advertisers, The Perfect Palette LLC automatically receives and stores certain types of information including IP address, web pages viewed, date and time, and responses to advertisements delivered by The Perfect Palette LLC's proprietary technology (“The Perfect Palette LLC Tech”), or third-party ad serving technologies. 

**We also collect:**

• **Information you provide:**  The Perfect Palette LLC may collect and maintain (or third parties with whom The Perfect Palette LLC has contracted, may collect and maintain on The Perfect Palette LLC's behalf) information that you provide to us during your visit to a The Perfect Palette Site. For example, you may provide information to the Site when you register, sign-in, search, participate in a test profile, survey or special offers, request our e-mail newsletters, or communicate with The Perfect Palette LLC's customer service. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with personally identifiable information such as your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and personal shopping and product preferences.

•  **Device data:**  We may collect data from the device you are using, including location data, what type of device it is, what operating system you are using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. You also may give us permission to access your information in other services. For example, you may be able to link your Facebook or Twitter account to a The Perfect Palette LLC Site, which allows us to obtain information from those accounts (like your friends or contacts). The information we get from those services often depends on your settings or their privacy policies, so be sure to check what those are.

•  **Device attributes:** information such as the operating system, hardware and software versions, battery level, signal strength, available storage space, browser type, app and file names and types, and plugins.

•  **Device operations:** information about operations and behaviors performed on the device, such as whether a window is foregrounded or backgrounded, or mouse movements (which can help distinguish humans from bots).

•  **Identifiers:** unique identifiers, device IDs, and other identifiers, such as from games, apps or accounts you use, and Family Device IDs.

•  **Device signals:** Bluetooth signals, and information about nearby Wi-Fi access points, beacons, and cell towers.

•  **Data from device settings:** information you allow us to receive through device settings you turn on, such as access to your GPS location, camera or photos.

• ** ** **Network and connections:** information such as the name of your mobile operator or ISP, language, time zone, mobile phone number, IP address, connection speed and, in some cases, information about other devices that are nearby or on your network.

•  **Cookie data:** data from cookies stored on your device, including cookie IDs and settings.

**2\. Use of Cookies, Log Files, The Perfect Palette LLC Tech, Devices and Other Technology.**

• The Perfect Palette LLC may use “cookies” to collect or log certain information. A cookie is a small piece of information that a website stores on a personal computer and which it can later retrieve. The Perfect Palette LLC may also use cookies for informational purposes, for example, to store your preferences for certain kinds of products or to serve advertisements tailored to your preferences.

• If you are uncomfortable with the use of cookie technology, you may get more information on how to opt out of our cookies at any time by emailing chrissy@theperfectpalette.com. Please note, if you use more than one type of browser, or more than one computer to access the Internet, you wil need to opt out in each browser and on each computer that you use. Certain types of The Perfect Palette LLC services, however, could be dependent on cookies, and you may disable those services by refusing cookies.

• Third parties including advertising networks and advertisers may also serve ads and these third parties may also use their own cookies. The Perfect Palette LLC does not control these cookies or the data collection practices of these companies. For more information about these companies’ separate privacy policies, practices, and use of cookies, you should contact the advertising network directly.  
**  
3\. Data Collection for Advertising.**

• The non-personally identifiable information collected is used to provide relevant, targeted advertising and improve The Perfect Palette LLC's advertising technology; monitor website traffic; collect statistical data; determine the effectiveness of advertisements and content; and collect data across multiple websites to categorize likely consumer interest segments for use in online behavioral advertising (“OBA”).

• The Perfect Palette LLC may track visits to its sites and this information may be used over time to help predict your consumer interest segments and select the ad content you see. The Perfect Palette LLC may also use non-personally identifiable profile-based anonymous information with other non-personally identifiable information that The Perfect Palette LLC has obtained from The Perfect Palette Tech, third-party ad serving technologies, the The Perfect Palette Network, and Non-Affiliated Sites.

• The Perfect Palette LLC may use personally identifiable information (information including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to the The Perfect Palette LLC Sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. We may share your personally identifiable information with third parties or affiliates of The Perfect Palette LLC with whom we have contracted to perform services on our behalf. All companies that act on our behalf are contractually obligated to keep the personal information we provide to them confidential and to use the personal information we share only to provide the services we ask them to perform.

**4\. Other Reasons We Collect Information about You and How.**

• Website Usage. The Perfect Palette LLC or The Perfect Palette LLC's authorized service providers may observe activities, preferences, and transactional data (such as your IP address, browser type, and operating system) relating to your use of The Perfect Palette Sites. The Perfect Palette LLC may use this collected or logged information in order to provide better service, to facilitate our customers’ use of the websites, to track usage of the websites, and to address security hazards. The Perfect Palette LLC, or one of The Perfect Palette LLC's authorized service providers, may also use this information to track aggregate traffic patterns. We may use aggregated, statistical information to describe our customer audience, products and services, and to develop partnerships with third parties to offer products and services in which we believe our customers will be interested.

• Online Transactions. You may visit a The Perfect Palette Site without registering, but if you enter a sweepstakes or contest, or use other special features that may be offered on our site, you may need to provide us with certain information such as your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, to open an account with us. We may share your personal information with third parties or affiliates of The Perfect Palette LLC where it is necessary for us to complete a transaction or do something you have asked us to do. We may also use this information to assist you in creating a user ID and a password to protect your account information and facilitate your use of special features or to complete a transaction.

• Using Public Areas of The Perfect Palette Sites. Any information disclosed in public areas of the The Perfect Palette LLC Sites, is public information that may be viewed and collected by any party. We cannot control the use of information disclosed in the social networking, chat rooms, reviews, or bulletin board portions of these Sites.

• You should exercise caution when disclosing information, including photos or images, in public areas of websites and should refrain from disclosing personally identifying information. If you wish to use some of the public portions on these Sites, we will direct you to first create a public ID, which is not your real e-mail address, before you can post information to our Site. The Perfect Palette LLC reserves the right to remove any information at any time from the The Perfect Palette LLC Sites that we deem inappropriate or for any other reason.

**5\. Data Sharing with 3rd parties.**

• We may sell your personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information to third parties for any reason. We may disclose your personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information to unaffiliated third parties who may want to offer you their own products and services. We may share your personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information with third parties, or affiliates of The Perfect Palette LLC where it is necessary for us to complete a transaction or do something you have asked us to do.

• For example, we might need to provide your personally identifiable information to third parties, such as advertisers, featured on a The Perfect Palette LLC Site, or through a website participating in the The Perfect Palette LLC Network or a Non-Affiliated Site so they can process and fulfill your request for more information from them. We may share your personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information with third parties with whom we have contracted to perform services on our behalf, or affiliates of The Perfect Palette LLC.

• All companies that act on our behalf are contractually obligated to keep the personal information we provide to them confidential and to use the personal information we share only to provide the services we ask them to perform.

• We may disclose personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information about our customers as permitted or required by law, such as in connection with a subpoena or similar legal process, or in connection with a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy, as discussed.  
**  
6\. Data Retention.**

• Personal Data. Personal data shall be kept for as long as is necessary for the purposes as described herein. We may store personal data for longer periods insofar as the personal data will be processed solely for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes. If you wish for us to cease storing your personal data, please email chrissy@theperfectpalette.co.

• Non-personally Identifiable Data. The Perfect Palette LLC is required to retain certain non–personally identifiable information collected from users of the The Perfect Palette LLC Sites, Affiliated Sites and Non-Affiliated Sites in order to provide audited information to advertisers and auditors. As a result, ad reporting and delivery data is retained for as long as is necessary for these purposes. Some of the ad reporting and delivery data may be aggregated for statistical purposes and retained indefinitely.

• Certain aggregated, non-personally identifiable information including historical data and attributes collected by The Perfect Palette LLC prior to an opt out election and which represent large numbers of users combined into aggregated statistical data and information shall be kept despite the fact that the user has opted out. Some of the aggregated, non-personally identifiable information may be further aggregated for statistical purposes and retained indefinitely.

• Additionally, The Perfect Palette LLC reserves the right to retain and use any information described in this Privacy and Security Policy as reasonably necessary to comply with all laws or regulations, regardless of any limitations set forth in this Policy. The Perfect Palette LLC reserves the right to change its data retention policy and the new data retention policy shall apply to all data collected following such change.

**7\. Security Practices.**

• Our internal data security policies restrict access to customers’ personal information to authorized employees. Authorized employees may use our customers’ personal information for The Perfect Palette LLC business purposes only. Our employees are bound by The Perfect Palette LLC policies that require them to maintain the confidentiality of our customers’ personal information. Employees who violate these requirements are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that are designed to guard our customers’ personal information. For example, for the security of your online visit to a The Perfect Palette LLC Site, we may make use of firewall barriers, encryption techniques, and/or authentication procedures. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure.

• As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, The Perfect Palette LLC cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. In the event of a breach of the confidentiality or security of your personal information, we will notify you as necessary, so you can take appropriate protective steps. Unless you indicate otherwise, we may notify you under such circumstances using the e-mail address you provided to us when you registered with the The Perfect Palette LLC Site.

• You should be careful to maintain the secrecy of your passwords and/or account information and be responsible about protecting your personal information and identity whenever you are online.

**8\. Links to Third-Party Sites.**

• The Perfect Palette LLC may contain links to third-party sites, which are maintained by third parties. Please be aware that The Perfect Palette LLC is not responsible for and cannot control the privacy policies of these other linked sites or their practices. We encourage you to read the privacy policies on these sites for applicable privacy practices relating to personally identifiable information you may choose to provide in interacting with these websites and the non-personally identifiable information collected through the use of cookies and other technologies collected via those sites because they may differ from The Perfect Palette LLC's privacy practices.

**9\. The Perfect Palette LLC Sites Are Not for Use by Children.**

• Children are not eligible to use The Perfect Palette LLC Sites. We ask that minors (under the age of 18) only use The Perfect Palette LLC Sites in conjunction with your parents or guardians. If you learn that your minor child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us.

**10\. Mergers, Acquisitions, and Bankruptcy.**

• If The Perfect Palette LLC should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, or if The Perfect Palette LLC should decide to buy another business or sell or reorganize part or all of The Perfect Palette LLC's business, The Perfect Palette LLC may be required to disclose both the information you provide to The Perfect Palette LLC and the information gathered by The Perfect Palette LLC to prospective or actual purchasers and other parties. It is The Perfect Palette LLC's practice to obtain appropriate protections for information disclosed in these types of transactions. The Perfect Palette LLC cannot, however, guarantee that The Perfect Palette LLC's Privacy and Security Policy will remain unchanged if The Perfect Palette LLC is sold or merges with another company.  
**  
11\. Managing Your Privacy Choices.**

**Updating Your Contact Preferences and Personal Information on The Perfect Palette LLC Sites.**

• You have choices when it comes to how The Perfect Palette LLC uses your personal information. When you register online with a The Perfect Palette LLC Site you can choose not to receive communications from us by e-mail. If you elect not to receive information by e-mail, The Perfect Palette LLC may continue to contact you as necessary to service your account. You can change your contact preferences at any time by following the instructions on the applicable The Perfect Palette LLC Site.

• Keeping your account information accurate and up-to-date is very important, so we can provide you with excellent service. If your account information is incomplete, inaccurate, or not current, please follow the instructions on the applicable The Perfect Palette LLC Site to correct your account information online. If you need additional assistance, please contact The Perfect Palette LLC customer service at chrissy@theperfectpalette.com.

**Opt Out: The Perfect Palette LLC.**

• If you would like to opt out from receiving customized, targeted advertisements from The Perfect Palette LLC based upon non-personally identifiable information, you may get more information on how to opt out by emailing chrissy@theperfectpalette.com.

• Opting out will not remove advertisements. You will continue to see advertisements provided by The Perfect Palette LLC, but the advertising will not be customized or targeted based on non-personally identifiable information collected by The Perfect Palette LLC. Please note that if you change computers or browsers, you will need to repeat this process for each computer and each browser.

**Deleting Your Information.**

You have the right to obtain the erasure of personal data without undue delay. Please contact chrissy@theperfectpalette.com if you would like us to delete your personal data.

**12\. This Privacy and Security Policy Applies to U.S. Customers.**

• If you are visiting our Site from outside of the United States, please be aware that you are sending information (including personal data) to the United States where our servers are located. That information may then be transferred within in the Unites States or back out of the United States to other countries outside of your country of residence, depending on the type of information and how it is stored by us.

• These countries (including the United States) may not have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in your country of residence; however, our collection, storage and use of your personal data will at all times continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy. In addition, such data may be stored on servers located outside your resident jurisdiction, which may have less stringent privacy practices than your own.  
**  
****13\. Contact Information.**

• If you have questions regarding your user account, our Privacy and Security Policy, your privacy choices, our Terms of Service, or any other topic, we are always happy to answer any questions or concerns you may have. You may email us at chrissy@theperfectpalette.com.

• The Perfect Palette LLC is a member of [The Brideclick Network](http://www.brideclick.net/privacy-policy/) and [rewardStyle](https://www.liketoknow.it/legal/privacy). Please click through to read their privacy policies as we do feature display advertisements from these networks.
